#### Dr.ANISH JOHN A

Email: anishj@vjcet.org

### Ph:9961734244

Dr. Anish John A works as the Assistant Professor in the Department of Management Studies. He completed his Engineering in Electrical and Electronics and MBA (Marketing) from Dr.GRD College of Science, Coimbatore. Subsequently he completed Doctorate in Management from Bharathiar University, Coimbatore. He has published various research papers in Peer reviewed and refereed journals including UGC approved journal and has presented research papers in various National and International Conferences.

## **Educational Qualification**

- PhD (Management) from Bharathiar University, Coimbatore.
- MBA (Marketing) from Dr.GRD College of Science, Coimbatore, affiliated to Bharathair University, Coimbatore (2010).
- B. E (Electrical and Electronics Engineering) from P.S.N.A College Engineering and Technology, Dindigul affiliated to Anna University, Chennai (2008).

## **Work Experience**

- 2016-2021: Assistant Professor, Department of Commerce and Management, Marygiri College of Arts and Science, Koothattukulam.
- 2015-2016: Assistant Professor, Department of Management Studies ,Naipunnya School of Management, Cherthala.
- 2013-2015: Assistant Professor, Mar Kuriakose Arts & Science College, Puthuvely.
- 2011-2013: Assistant Professor, Al Azhar College of Arts and Science, Thodupuzha.
- 2010-2011: Sales Engineer, Rons Enterprises, Gurgaon.

### **Areas of Interest:**

Marketing Management, Brand Management, Consumer Behaviour, Operations Management & Quality Management.

#### **Publications**

• Anish John A & DR.C.Sengottuvelu (2021). "Factors influencing smartphone purchase intention among generation z", Wesleyan Journal of Research (IJRAR), Volume -14, Issue -1, January, 2021, Page 125-144, ISSN (Print):0975-1386.

- Anish John A & DR.C.Sengottuvelu (2021). Buying Behaviour towards smartphone among generation z", *The Journal of Oriental Research Madras*, *Volume 92, Issue -1, January, 2021, Page 296-312, ISSN(Print) :0022-3301*.
- Anish John A & DR.C.Sengottuvelu (2021). "Gender difference on factors affecting purchase intention of smartphone among generation z", *International Journal of Research and Analytical Reviews (IJRAR), Volume -5, Issue -8, October-December, 2018, Page 152u-157u, ISSN(Print):2349-5138,*
- Anish John A & DR.C.Sengottuvelu (2021). "Social factors influencing the smartphone purchase among the generation z", International Journal of Human Resource Management and Research Volume-8, Issue-5, August-October, 2018, Page 1-10, ISSN(Print): 2249-6874,
- Anish John A (2015). "The influence of surprise toys on repeat purchase among kids with special reference to kinder joy", International journal of social science and humanities research.vol.3, issue 4. ISSN 2348-164.
- Anish John A, Sarika & Renju (2015). "Mobile banking in India-Opportunities & Challenges", Finova'15, Green Banking, ISBN 978-93-85105-19-7.
- Anish John A& Sarika (2015). "Preschool Children & Surprise toys" Synernovae '15, ISBN 978-0070682139.

# FDP's/Workshops/Seminars/Conference Attended

- Attended webinar on "Enlightening the Brand Building-Audience Response Link" organized by Emerald Publishing on 29/05/2023.
- Attended International webinar on "Supply chain Management and Systems" organized by School of Management Studies, University of Hyderabad in association with Oracle Cloud Team, USA from January 05 January 09, 2022.
- Attended International webinar on "Contemporary issues in Globalization and Sustainability of Supply chain" organized by Viswajyothi School of Management Studies & John. A. Walker College of Business, USA on 19<sup>th</sup> March 2022.
- Attended Online Elementary FDP on "Applications of Blockchain Technology and AI in Services Sector" from 20/09/2021 to 24/09/2021.
- Attended Online Advanced FDP on "Applications of Blockchain Technology and AI in Services Sector" organized by AICTE Training and Learning (ATAL) Academy and Acharya Bangalore B School from 15/11/2021 to 19/11/2021.
- Attended online FDP on "Pedagogy and Scholarly writing" organized by Indian Institute of Management, Visakhapatnam from 05/07/2021 to 09/07/2021.

- Attended FDP on "Statistical Tools and Techniques for Scientific Research" organized by Amaljyothi College of Engineering, Kanjirapally. from July 26-28,2021.
- Attended international conference(online) on "Economics of Happiness and Welfare" organized by St. Joseph College, Irinjalakuda & Sacred Heart College, Chalakuddy from 18/06/2021 to 19/06/2021.
- Attended Online Workshop on "Empowering Rural Consumers" organized by School of Commerce, Bharathiar University from 19/11/2021 to 20/01/2021
- Attended International webinar on "Research, Thesis & Paper Publication" by Cambridge Research Training on 12<sup>th</sup> September 2021.
- Attended FDP on "User Friendly Tools For Online Teaching And Assessment" on 24<sup>th</sup>
  July to 30<sup>th</sup> July,2020, organized by Prajyoti Niketan College,Pudukkad.
- Attended two days international webinar on "Emerging business trends post covid 19" on 30&31 August 2020, conducted by Bangalore University associated with Acharya Bangalore B School.
- Attended online workshop on "Art of thesis Writing" organized by Rehoboth Academic Services, Bangalore on 8 August 2020.
- Presented paper in two days Multidisciplinary International Academic research conference (ISBN:9780989515047) on the theme "Buying Behaviour of smartphones among undergraduate students" organized by Anna University-PSGIM-ARC at Coimbatore,18<sup>th</sup> &19<sup>th</sup> February 2016.
- Presented paper in one day Multidisciplinary Paper presentation conference on the theme "Pre-School Children and surprise toys" organized by Naipunnya school of Management at Cherthala, 5<sup>th</sup> December 2015.
- Attended two days workshop on "Research Methodology and Application of Statistical Tools" organized by SCMS Cochin School of Business on June 26<sup>th</sup> & 27<sup>th</sup>,2015.
   Conducted by Prof. (Dr.) K. Kalyanaraman (Former Professor &Head, Dept. of Statistics, Kerala University).
- Attended one day Seminar on "Research Methodology and Application of Statistical Tools" on December 5<sup>th</sup> 2015. Conducted by Dr.R.Gopal (Director,D Y Patil University, Mumbai).
- Attended one day Seminar on "Research Paper writing" on June 1<sup>st</sup> 2015. Conducted by Dr.Kevin (Former Pro Vice Chancellor, University of Kerala).

- Attended one day Seminar on "Research Methodology and Research Paper writing" on March 3<sup>rd</sup> 2015. Conducted by Prof. Ajay Saraf (Professor ,Dr.D.Y.Patil University,Mumbai).
- Attended one day Seminar on "Student Counselling and Communication" on October 10th 2015. Conducted by Prof. Jameela P(Principal ,KVM College of special Education,Cherthala).
- Attended FDP, conducted by Minds Training Academy, 1<sup>st</sup>-5<sup>th</sup>June 2015.
- Attended one day Seminar on "Orientation towards NAAC Implementation" on January 1<sup>st</sup> 2015 Conducted by Dr.Joseph P.X(Professor, Rajagiri College of Social Sciences).